Register of the O. J. (Oliver Julian) Todd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
O. J. (Oliver Julian) Todd papers
1899-1973
73087
Hoover Institution Archives
68 manuscript boxes, 7 oversize boxes, memorabilia (31.2 linear feet)
Diaries, speeches and writings, correspondence, reports, memoranda, and photographs relating to engineering projects in China, especially river engineering and flood control; famines and relief work in China; and social, economic and political conditions in China. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Todd, O. J. (Oliver Julian)
Access
Microfilm use only, except boxes 58 and 60-63. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Available on microfilm (82 reels). Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1880 Nov. 1 Born in Colon, Michigan
1908 B.S. degree in Civil Engineering, University of Michigan
1909-1917 Field Assistant, Chief Hydrographer, and Assistant Engineer for the City of San Francisco; worked on the Hetch Hetchy water supply system and the Twin Peaks Tunnel
1917-1919 Captain in the Engineering Corps, U.S. Army
1919-1921 Principal Assistant Engineer for the Chinese government's Grand Canal Improvement Board
1921 Field Manager and Chief Engineer for American National Red Cross in Shantung (4 months)
1921-1923 Chief Engineer for the Asia Development Company
1923-1935 Chief Engineer for the China International Famine Relief Commission
1927 Married Dr. Lois Pendelton
1935-1938 Consulting Engineer to the China International Famine Relief Commission, to the American Advisory Board of Shanghai, to the Shantung Government on the Yellow River, to the Yellow River Commission, and to the Friendship Fund of New York City
1938 April Returned to the United States and settled in Palo Alto, California
1940-1942 Engineer for the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation
1942-1945 Regional Engineer, Area Engineer and Senior Engineer with the United States Army Engineers in Arizona
1945-1947 Advisor to the Yellow River Project of the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration in China
1948 Democratic candidate for U.S. Congress in the 8th District
1949-1951 Chief of the Irrigation Engineering Division of the Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction in China
1973 Author, The China That I Knew
1974 Jan. 13 Died, Palo Alto, California
Scope and Contents Note
Diaries, speeches and writings, correspondence, reports, memoranda, and photographs relating to engineering projects in China, especially river engineering and flood control; famines and relief work in China; and social, economic and political conditions in China.
China International Famine Relief Commission.; United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration.; Engineering--China.; Engineers.; Famines--China.; Flood control--China.; International relief.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--China.; River engineering--China.; Yellow River (China)
- Microfilm Reel Content Guide
  Other Finding Aids note
  Downloadable PDF file of the Microfilm Reel Content Guide
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1899-1973
  Scope and Contents note
  Family and personal correspondence, diaries, memberships, military service records, financial records and passports arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - General
    - General, 1931-1969 (Reel 1)
      Box/Folder 1: 1-2. Includes Christmas cards sent.
    - Printed matter
      - Clippings of printed interviews and quotations
        Box/Folder 1: 3
      - We Seven: A Family Story, by Donna Todd McBryan
        Box/Folder 1: 4
  - Biographical data
    Box/Folder 1: 5
  - Correspondence, 1899-1964
    - General
      - General
        - 1899-1909
          Box/Folder 1: 6
        - 1919-1920
          Box/Folder 1: 7
        - 1922
          Box/Folder 1: 8
        - 1923
          Box/Folder 1: 9
        - 1924
          Box/Folder 1: 10
        - 1925 (Reel 2)
          Box/Folder 1: 11
        - 1926
          Box/Folder 1: 12
        - 1927
          Box/Folder 2: 1
        - 1928
          Box/Folder 2: 2
        - 1929
          Box/Folder 2: 3
        - 1930-1934
          Box/Folder 2: 4
        - 1935
          Box/Folder 2: 5
        - 1936
          Box/Folder 2: 6
        - 1937
          Box/Folder 2: 7
        - 1938 (Reel 3)
          Box/Folder 2: 8
        - 1939
          Box/Folder 2: 9
        - 1940-1950
          Box/Folder 2: 10
      - American Advisory Committee, The China Council, Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A., 1936-1937
        Box/Folder 2: 11
      - Barrett, David, 1934-1955
        Box/Folder 2: 12
      - Buell, Emma, 1926
        Box/Folder 2: 13
      - Clubb, Oliver Edmund, 1940-1952
        Box/Folder 2: 14
      - Gould, Randall, 1926-1949
        Box/Folder 2: 15
      - Johnson, Hewlett, 1932-1954
        Box/Folder 2: 16
      - Judd, Walter H., 1939-1945
        Box/Folder 2: 17
      - Lowdermilk, Walter Clay, 1924-1951
        Box/Folder 2: 18
      - Snow, Edgar, 1935-1964
        Box/Folder 2: 19. See also Democracy.
      - Spence, Jonathan, 1967
        Box/Folder 2: 20
      - Tucker, Francis F., 1920-1947
        Box/Folder 2: 21
      - University of Michigan, 1921-1946
        Box/Folder 2: 22
    - Family
      - General, undated - 1949 (Reel 4)
        Box/Folder 3: 1
      - Crow, Vera (sister) and Ralph
        - 1901-1937
          Box/Folder 3: 2
        - 1938-1955
          Box/Folder 3: 3
      - Kahn, Joseph H. (brother-in-law), 1924-1929
        Box/Folder 3: 4
      - Larimore, Adaline, 1929, 1944
        Box/Folder 3: 5
      - Pendleton, J. L. (mother-in-law), 1927-1945
        Box/Folder 3: 6
      - Pendleton, Lois (second wife)
        - 1924-1932
          Box/Folder 3: 7
        - 1940-1951
          Box/Folder 3: 8
      - Pendleton, Morris (brother-in-law) (Reel 5)
        Box/Folder 4: 1
      - Pendleton, Robert (brother-in-law), 1927-1951
        Box/Folder 4: 2
      - Pendleton family (general), 1928-1947
        Box/Folder 4 :3
      - Price, William (uncle and cousin), 1905-1907
        Box/Folder 4: 4
      - Todd, Albert (cousin), 1936-1948
        Box/Folder 4: 5
      - Todd, Alfred (brother)
        - 1899-1905
          Box/Folder 4: 6
        - 1906-1926
          Box/Folder 4: 7
        - 1927-1932 (Reel 6)
          Box/Folder 4: 8
        - 1934-1939
          Box/Folder 4: 9
        - 1940-1955
          Box/Folder 4: 10
      - Todd, Charles (nephew), 1928-1944
        Box/Folder 5: 1
      - Todd, David (nephew), 1944-1945
        Box/Folder 5: 2
      - Todd, Donna (sister), 1901-1954
        Box/Folder 5: 3
      - Todd, Doris (daughter), 1943-1950
        Box/Folder 5: 4
      - Todd, Dwight (cousin), 1944-1945
        Box/Folder 5: 5
      - Todd, Elinor (daughter), 1940-1955
        Box/Folder 5: 6
      - Todd, Hewlett (son), 1944-1951
        Box/Folder 5: 7
      - Todd, James (son), 1943-1951
        Box/Folder 5: 8
      - Todd, Julia (mother)
        - 1900-1920 (Reel 7)
          Box/Folder 5: 9
        - 1921-1935
          Box/Folder 5: 10
        - 1936-1942
          Box/Folder 5: 11
      - Todd, Laurence (brother)
        - 1904-1934
          Box/Folder 5: 12
        - 1935-1939 (Reel 8)
          Box/Folder 6: 1
        - 1940-1955
          Box/Folder 6: 2
      - Todd, Lois P. See Pendleton, Lois
      - Todd, O. H. (father), 1900-1929
        Box/Folder 6: 3
      - Todd, Priscilla (niece), 1925-1935
        Box/Folder 6: 4
      - Todd, Robert (son), 1918-1948 (Reel 9)
        Box/Folder 6: 5
      - Todd, Sally (cousin), 1926-1927
        Box/Folder 6: 6
      - Todd, Victor (brother)
        - 1905-1929
          Box/Folder 6: 7
        - 1930-1961
          Box/Folder 7: 1
        - 1962-1967
          Box/Folder 7: 2
      - Todd, Walter (brother), 1905-1951 (Reel 10)
        Box/Folder 7: 3
      - Todd, William (cousin), 1944-1945
        Box/Folder 7: 4
      - Zimmerman, Rheta (first wife)
        - 1918-1922
          Box/Folder 7: 5
        - 1923-1925
          Box/Folder 7: 6
        - 1926
          Box/Folder 7: 7
        - 1927-1937
          Box/Folder 7: 8
  - Diaries, 1915-1951 (Reels 10-19)
    Boxes 8-10
  - Subject file
    - Early years correspondence
      - Brodhead, Daisy, 1903-1928 (Reel 20)
        Box/Folder 11A: 1
      - Johnson, H. E., 1904-1907
        Box/Folder 11A: 2
      - Strong, Elizabeth, 1904-1905
        Box/Folder 11A: 3
      - Ryan, Willis, 1906-1918
        Box/Folder 11A: 4
    - Education, 1899-1908
      Box/Folder 11A: 5
    - Essential Oil Products Company, 1920-1939 (Reel 21)
      Box/Folder 11B: 6
    - Finances
      - General, 1898-1927
        Box/Folder 11B: 7
      - General, 1928-1940
        Box/Folder 12: 1
      - Taxes, 1919-1926
        Box/Folder 12: 2
    - Later years, 1938-1974
      - General correspondence, 1938-1971
        Box/Folder 12: 3
      - China support groups, Interest in
        - General, 1939-1940
          Box/Folder 12: 4
        - American Friends of the Chinese People, 1939-1940 (Reel 22)
          Box/Folder 12: 5
        - Palo Alto Committee Against War Shipments to Japan
          Box/Folder 12: 6
        - Palo Alto Committee for Civilian Relief in China, 1939-1940
          Box/Folder 12: 7
      - Civil Service-Retirement
        Box/Folder 12: 8
      - Congress, Candidate for, 1948
        Box/Folder 12: 9
      - Job hunting
        Box/Folder 12: 10
    - Memberships
      - General
        Box/Folder 12: 11
      - American Society of Civil Engineers
        Box/Folder 12: 12
      - American Society of Civil Engineers
        Box/Folder 13A: 1
      - Association of Chinese and American Engineers (Reel 23)
        Box/Folder 13A: 2
      - Friendly societies, 1907-1974
        Box/Folder 13A: 3-4
      - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1939-1950
        Box/Folder 13A: 5
    - Military service, 1917-1919
      - General (Reel 24)
        Box/Folder 13B: 6
      - General
        Box/Folder 14: 1
      - Architectural specifications for a base hospital at St. Parize-le-Chatel, France, 1918
        Box/Folder 14: 2
      - Correspondence, 1917-1920
        - General
          Box/Folder 14: 3
        - Brooks, Joe, 1919
          Box/Folder 14: 4
        - San Francisco Engineering Association
          Box/Folder 14: 5
      - Finances and invoices (Reel 25)
        Box/Folder 14: 6
      - The Martian, issues, 1918-1919
        Box/Folder 14: 7
      - Memoranda
        Box/Folder 14: 8
      - Officer's Reserve Corps file (Reel 26)
        Box/Folder 14: 9
      - Orders
        Box/Folder 14: 10
      - Travel guidebooks, maps (Reels 26-27)
        Box/Folder 15: 1-4
    - Mirrors, Chinese bronze (Reel 27)
      Box/Folder 16: 1. Includes correspondence, descriptions, and lists. See also MEMORABILIA.
    - Travel
      - General
        Box/Folder 16: 2
      - Passports and safe conduct passes
        Box/Folder 16: 3
      - Leave (return to the United States), 1935
        Box/Folder 16: 4
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1899-1973
  Articles, drafts and outlines of speeches and books and correspondence with editors arranged chronologically by title.
  - General outlines, notes, and background material, undated - 1972 (Reel 28)
    Box/Folder 16: 5-6
  - "Territorial Expansion for the United States," Debate topic, High school, Kalamazoo, Michigan, typescript, 1899
    Box/Folder 16: 7
  - "Road Building in Hunan Province, China," The Overseas Highway Magazine, printed copy, 1924
    Box/Folder 16: 8
  - "American Engineers in the China Field," The Military Engineer, correspondence, printed copy, 1924 January-February
    Box/Folder 16: 9
  - "Famine Releif (sic) Work," The North China Standard, clipping, 1924 May 11
    Box/Folder 16: 10
  - 1924 July 26
    Box/Folder 16: 11
  - "The 1924-25 Engineering Program for Flood Relief," The China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1924 December 6
    Box/Folder 16: 12
  - "Shantung Floods of 1925 Due to Breaks in Yellow River Dykes," The China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1925 December 5
    Box/Folder 16: 13
  - Miscellaneous, 1926
    Box/Folder 16: 14. Correspondence and book (contract) agreement.
  - The Open Road in China, 1926 (Reels 28-29)
    Boxes 17A-17B. Four typescript drafts of the manuscript and photographs to accompany the text.
  - "Modern Highways in China," address, Chinese Engineering Society convention, printed copy, 1926 August 24 (Reel 30)
    Box/Folder 18: 1
  - "Engineers in Foreign War Zones," The Military Engineer, notes and printed copy, 1926 September-October
    Box/Folder 18: 2
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and outline, 1927
    Box/Folder 18: 3
  - "Construction Enterprises in South-west China," Chinese Economic Journal, printed copy, 1927 June
    Box/Folder 18: 4
  - "Repairing Dikes and Revolutions on the Upper Yangtsze," The China Weekly Review printed copy, 1927 July 23
    Box/Folder 18: 5
  - "Motor Roads for South China," The Far Eastern Review, printed copy, 1927 November
    Box/Folder 18: 6
  - "China International Famine Relief Commission; Report of the Engineering Department," The Far Eastern Review, printed copy, 1927 December
    Box/Folder 18: 7
  - "The Good Roads Movement in Kweichow," The China Weekly Review, printed copy and review, 1927 December 24
    Box/Folder 18: 8
  - "Road Construction Continues in China Despite the War!" The China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1927 December 31
    Box/Folder 18: 9
  - Miscellaneous, 1928
    Box/Folder 18: 10. Correspondence, outline, and draft.
  - Drafts of five articles not published, correspondence and typescript copies, 1928
    Box/Folder 18: 11
  - "The Program of the C.I.F.R.C.: Constructive Work, With International Cooperation, Emphasized," The Peking Leader, clipping, 1928 February (Reel 31)
    Box/Folder 18: 12
  - "Construction Enterprises in South-west China," The Far Eastern Review, 1928 September
    Box/Folder 18: 13. Appeared originally in Chinese Economic Journal, 1927 June.
  - "Assuring China's Food Supply," China, printed copy, 1928 October
    Box/Folder 18: 14
  - " A Commission That Has Succeeded in China," Pan Pacific Progress, printed copy, 1928 November
    Box/Folder 18: 15
  - "Famine Prevention in China," The Chinese Christian Student, printed copy, 1928 November
    Box/Folder 18: 16
  - Review of China's Millions by Anna Louise Strong, Survey Graphic, correspondence and printed copy, 1928 December
    Box/Folder 18: 17
  - "Highways in a Land of Barriers," Asia, correspondence and printed copy, 1929 January
    Box/Folder 18: 18
  - "A Practical Educational Movement," The China Weekly Review, printed copy, 1929 January 26
    Box/Folder 18: 19
  - "Kaifeng Now Much Improved; Educational Work Emphasized," The Peking Leader, clipping, 1929 February 22
    Box/Folder 18: 20
  - "Engineering and Altruism in China," Paper, World Engineering Congress, Tokyo, clipping and printed copies, 1929
    Box/Folder 18: 21
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1930
    Box/Folder 18: 22
  - "The Yellow River," The Week in China, reprint of an address given March 6 at the North China Union Language School, Peiping, 1930 March 8
    Box/Folder 18: 23
  - "Economics of Highways for China," The Chinese Social and Political Review, printed copy, 1930 April
    Box/Folder 18: 24
  - "Getting Yellow River Water on the Saratsi Plain," The Far Eastern Review, printed copy, 1931 February
    Box/Folder 18: 25
  - "Helping to Raise Standards of Living in China," Pan Pacific Progress, two printed, copies, 1931 March-April (Reel 32)
    Box/Folder 19: 1
  - "Good Roads Exhibition; An Expert's Tribute," North-China Daily News, clipping, 1931 October 6
    Box/Folder 19: 2
  - "Famine Prevention and Relief Projects," The Far Eastern Review, notes and printed copy, 1932 August
    Box/Folder 19: 3
  - "The Wei Pei Irrigation Project in Shensi Province," by S. Eliassen and O. J. Todd. The China Journal, printed copy and reprint, 1932 October
    Box/Folder 19: 4
  - "Some Altruistic and Economic Aspects of Famine Prevention Work," The Chinese Recorder, printed copy and reprint, 1932 November
    Box/Folder 19: 5
  - "In Memoriam," a tribute to John R. Freeman. The Journal of the Association of Chinese and American Engineers, printed copy, 1933 January
    Box/Folder 19: 6
  - Speech notes, Language School, typescript, 1933 January 6, 20
    Box/Folder 19: 7
  - "The Wei Pei Irrigation Work," The Far Eastern Review, printed copy, 1933 February
    Box/Folder 19: 8
  - "Wrestling With Some of China's Rivers: Both Medieval and Modern Engineering Methods Applied to the Yangtze, the Yellow, and the Yung Ting," Civil Engineering, correspondence and reprint, 1933 June
    Box/Folder 19: 9
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, outline, and draft of an article, 1934
    Box/Folder 19: 10
  - China Travel and Other Verses, printed copy, circa 1934
    Box/Folder 19: 11
  - Hua Shan and Other Verses, printed copy, 1934
    Box/Folder 19: 12
  - "Regulation of the Fen Ho for Flood Protection and Conservancy of Winter Flow as an Aid to Irrigation," Part 1, The Far Eastern Review, printed copy, 1934 April
    Box/Folder 19: 13
  - "Regulation of the Fen Ho for Flood Protection and Conservancy of Winter Flow as an Aid to Irrigation," continued from April 1934, The Far Eastern Review, printed copy, 1934 May
    Box/Folder 19: 14
  - Article on the China International Famine Relief Commission, The China Press, clipping, 1934 October 1 (Reel 33)
    Box/Folder 19: 15
  - "The Si-Lan Road," The China Critic, printed copy, 1934 November 1
    Box/Folder 19: 16
  - "The Present Condition and a Discussion of the Fundamental Conservancy Measures for the Yellow River," typescript report, 1934
    Box/Folder 19: 17
  - Miscellaneous notes, typescript draft, and correspondence, 1935
    Box/Folder 19: 18
  - "Entrancing Kweichow and Her Neighbor Yunnan," unpublished article, circa 1935
    Box/Folder 20: 1
  - "Growth of Democracy in China," unpublished article, circa 1935
    Box/Folder 20: 2
  - "The Hope of China," unpublished article, circa 1935
    Box/Folder 20: 3
  - Article on the Wei Pei Irrigation Project, Shanghai Evening Post, clipping, 1935 February 4
    Box/Folder 20: 4
  - "Transportation in China," China, printed copy, 1935 April
    Box/Folder 20: 5
  - "A Review of the Saratsi Irrigation Project," Paper, Association of Chinese and American Engineers, Peiping, China, printed copy, 1935 April 6
    Box/Folder 20: 6
  - "A Review of the Saratsi Irrigation Project," Journal of the Association of Chinese and American Engineers, printed copy, 1935 May-June
    Box/Folder 20: 7
  - "Flood and Famine," Asia, correspondence, typescript, and printed copy, 1935 June
    Box/Folder 20: 8
  - Abstract of remarks on present engineering practice in China, American Institute of Construction Engineers, New York City, typescript, 1935 June 5
    Box/Folder 20: 9
  - "China's Floods and the Future," Survey Graphic, correspondence, typescript draft, and printed copy, 1935 October
    Box/Folder 20: 10
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and typescript drafts, 1936
    Box/Folder 20: 11
  - "Some Aspects of Famine Relief and Prevention in China," Digest of the Synodal Commission, correspondence, printed copy, and reprint, 1936 January
    Box/Folder 20: 12
  - Reports about the Huang Ho floods in newspapers: Peiping Chronicle, The Shanghai Evening Post, Peking & Tientsin Times, clippings and typescript, 1936
    Box/Folder 20: 13
  - "A Runaway River Controlled," Engineering News-Record, correspondence, typescript, and printed copy, 1936 May 21 (Reel 34)
    Box/Folder 20: 14
  - "Hydraulic and Road Questions in China," A Review of the Report by the Committee of Experts of the League of Nations, The Journal of the Association of Chinese and American Engineers, reprint, correspondence, and newspaper review, 1936 November-December
    Box/Folder 20: 15
  - The Yellow River and Other Verses, printed copy, 1936 December
    Box/Folder 20: 16
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and typescript draft, 1937
    Box/Folder 20: 17
  - "China's Ol' Man River," Scientific American, printed copy, 1937 January
    Box/Folder 20: 18
  - "River Problems in China," China, correspondence, transcript, and printed copy, 1937 February 15
    Box/Folder 20: 19
  - "Flood Control in China," Democracy, printed copy, 1937 June 8
    Box/Folder 20: 20
  - "The Progress of Irrigation in North China," Civil Engineering, correspondence and two reprints, 1937 August
    Box/Folder 20: 21
  - "The Engineer in China. His Opportunities for the Future," The Peiping Chronicle, clipping, 1937 October 24
    Box/Folder 20: 22
  - "The Engineer in China. His Opportunities for the Future," Peking & Tientsin Times, clipping, 1937 October 28
    Box/Folder 20: 23
  - "Engineering Experiences in China During the Last Two Decades," Engineering Journal, Hong Kong University, printed copy, 1937 December
    Box/Folder 20: 24
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, outlines for speeches, and background material, 1938
    Box/Folder 20: 25
  - Two Decades in China, correspondence and memoranda, 1938
    Box/Folder 21: 1
  - Yellow River Report, 1937, River Regulation Studies for China, printed copy, 1938 March
    Box/Folder 21: 2
  - "Engineering in War-torn China," Engineering News-Record, correspondence, typescript, and printed copy, 1938 May 5
    Box/Folder 21: 3
  - "The Yellow River Is 'Japan's Sorrow' Now," New York Times, correspondence and clipping, 1938 June 19
    Box/Folder 21: 4
  - "Yellow River Dragons Stir," New York Times Magazine, correspondence and clipping, 1938 June 19
    Box/Folder 21: 5
  - "The Yellow River Flood," Engineering News-Record, printed copy, 1938 June 23
    Box/Folder 21: 6
  - "Present-Day Irrigation Methods in China," Civil Engineering, correspondence, typescript draft, abstract, and two printed reprints, 1938 August
    Box/Folder 21: 7
  - "The Floods of 'China's Sorrow,'" The Military Engineer, notes, correspondence, and printed copy, 1938 September-October (Reel 35)
    Box/Folder 21: 8
  - "Regulation of the Yellow River," Journal of the Association of Chinese and American Engineers, printed copy, 1938 November-December
    Box/Folder 21: 9
  - "The Yellow River Problem," reprint from Proceedings, American Society of Civil Engineers, correspondence and printed copy, 1938 December
    Box/Folder 21: 10
  - Speech invitations and outlines, 1939
    Box/Folder 21: 11
  - Speech on China, East Bay Branch, American Association of University Women, correspondence and program, 1939 April 21
    Box/Folder 21: 12
  - "An American Engineer in China," speech, California Council, correspondence and outline, 1939 June 3
    Box/Folder 21: 13
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, outlines, and notes, 1940
    Box/Folder 21: 14
  - Verses From East and West, printed copy, 1941
    Box/Folder 21: 15
  - Miscellaneous, 1942
    Box/Folder 21: 16
  - "Taming Flood Dragons Along China's Hwang Ho," National Geographic Magazine, correspondence, typescript draft, and printed copy, 1942 February